<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jesus Aguilar</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jesus Aguilar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Exploratory Data Analysis</title>
      <link>/project/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project1/</guid>
      <description>The datasets ‘education’ and ‘wages’ were chosen for exploratory data analysis. The ‘education’ dataset contains a wide range of aspects for U.S. education (K-12) and finance mainly for the years 1992-2016, with our focus on revenue and expenditure. The ‘wages’ dataset contains minimum wages set by the states and the federal government for the years 1968-2020. After many hours of searching for data in the R datasets, I decided to turn to other sources.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modeling, Testing, and Predicting</title>
      <link>/project/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/project2/</guid>
      <description>The dataset “project1data” was derived from project 1 and we will be observing a subset of the original variables, a total of 9 variables and 1,200 observations. The dataset consists of student enrollment, revenue, expenditure, and minimum wage data across the 50 states of the U.S. through the years 1993-2016. There is also a ‘Percent’ variable which refers to the percent of expenditure contributed to instructional expenditure (educational purposes for grades K-12), and a ‘wage_cat’ variable which places the state in a low, intermediate, or high category based on that year’s minimum wage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description> Check out some of my coding projects below:
 Wrangling &amp;amp; Exploratory Data Analysis
 Modeling, Inference, Prediction
  -- </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>R &amp; Python Working Together</title>
      <link>/post/1/01/01/r-python-working-together/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/1/01/01/r-python-working-together/</guid>
      <description>There’s currently a hot debate in the world of coding today, and that is, which programming language is better, R or Python? Well something that can be agreed upon is that a bilingual person has a greater advantage over a monolingual speaker. So why not learn both programming languages if possible? Knowing both R and Python will give you a great advantage when trying to land a job. People often communicate using two languages and one can do exactly that with R and Python using the reticulate package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resume</title>
      <link>/resume/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/resume/</guid>
      <description>    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
